<!DOCTYPE kpartgui>
<effect tag="frei0r.lightgraffiti" id="frei0r.lightgraffiti">
        <name>Light Graffiti</name>
        <description>Light Graffiti effect.
        <full><![CDATA[This effect allows to do Light Painting (i.e. painting with light sources on a photo by keeping the shutter
        opened for a while), but for video.]]></full></description>
        <author>Simon A. Eugster (Granjow)</author>
        <parameter type="constant" name="sensitivity" default="100" min="0" max="500" factor="100">
            <name>Sensitivity</name>
            <comment><![CDATA[Light sensitivity.<br/>
            For slowly moving light source try to use a higher sensitivity to obtain smoother results.]]></comment>
        </parameter>
        <parameter type="constant" name="thresholdBrightness" default="450" min="0" max="765" factor="1">
            <name>Brightness Threshold</name>
            <comment><![CDATA[Determines how bright (<code>R+G+B</code>) a light source needs to be in order to be recognized as light source.<br/>
            Increasing this threshold requires brighter light sources (i.e. more white or less color, respectively) but prevents some «false alarms» where semi-bright parts, e.g. hands where colors can change quite a lot compared to the background, are incorrectly recognized as light source.]]></comment>
        </parameter>
        <parameter type="constant" name="thresholdDifference" default="80" min="0" max="255" factor="1">
            <name>Difference Threshold</name>
            <comment><![CDATA[Similar to the brightness threshold, but for the brightness difference (<code>max(dR, dG, dB)</code>) <em>relative to the calculated background.</em><br/>
            Increasing this threshold makes it harder for light sources to be accepted on bright backgrounds, but decreases the danger of noise counting as light source.]]></comment>
        </parameter>
        <parameter type="constant" name="thresholdDiffSum" default="0" min="0" max="765" factor="1">
            <name>Difference Sum Threshold</name>
            <comment><![CDATA[Threshold for the differences summed up (<code>dR + dG + dB</code>).<br/>
            Raising this value might, in some cases, avoid that some light objects lit by the light source are added to the light mask.]]></comment>
        </parameter>
        <parameter type="constant" name="dim" default="0" min="0" max="255" factor="255">
            <name>Dimming</name>
            <comment>Dims the light mask. Lights will leave a fainting trail if it is set to a value > 0.</comment>
        </parameter>
        <parameter type="constant" name="backgroundWeight" default="0" min="0" max="100" factor="100">
            <name>Background Weight</name>
            <comment>Strength of the (calculated) background image. Setting it to 100 paints the light mask directly over the background, without any person in the image if the video starts with a «clean» background image.</comment>
        </parameter>
        <parameter type="constant" name="longAlpha" default="0" min="0" max="256" factor="256">
                <name>α</name>
                <comment><![CDATA[Determines how the effect tries to adapt to background changes. <br/>
                If the background does not change, then try to use 0 (requires the first frame to represent background only, without your light sources).]]></comment>
        </parameter>
        <parameter type="bool" name="statsBrightness" default="0">
            <name>Show brightness statistics</name>
        </parameter>
        <parameter type="bool" name="statsDifference" default="0">
            <name>Show background difference statistics</name>
        </parameter>
        <parameter type="bool" name="transparentBackground" default="0">
            <name>Transparent Background</name>
        </parameter>
        <parameter type="bool" name="reset" default="0">
            <name>Reset the mask</name>
        </parameter>
</effect>
